# Manisha Chicheriya

## **Embedded Developer**

Bengluru manishachicheriya@gmail.com 7974223816 Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/manishachicheriya

An Embedded Software Engineer with 2+years of experience specializing in software development, RTOS and solution design. Analytical thinker leverages problem-solving skills to drive continuous improvement. Works crossfunctionally to adapt systems to changing business needs and formulate winning solutions.

## **Key Skills**

- Programming: Embedded C, Python.
   Java. C++
- Tools: MATLAB/Simulink, State flow, winAMS, Caseplayer
- Project Management Tools: JIRA, Azure
- Test Tools: Multi IDE, PyTest, Unit and Integration Test
- Configuration Management Tools: SVN, Tortoise Git, Git Bash.
- MISRA C, MAAB, ISO26262
- Networking: IPv4/6, TCP, UDP, FTP, HTTP

Communication Protocol:- SPI, I2C, UART Microcontroller:- ARM, Raspberry PI, STM32

### **Professional Experience**

System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services/Nissan | November 2020 - September 2022

- I have performed Unit and Integration Testing for the logic level of embedded C for various ADAS components .
- To achieve maximum reachability in Statement coverage, Branch coverage, Call Coverage(Integration Level) and MC/DC Coverage(Unit Level) by passing testcases manually in coverage master tool.
- Experience in System/system Integration/verification and validation testing related automotive domain like ADAS.
- Experience in creating test cases and test steps.

#### Embedded Software Developer

Tata Consultancy Services/Renault | November 2022 - Present

- Component owner for Object Equipment Manufacturer Diagnostic(OEM Diag).
- I am responsible for developing and implementing software for embedded systems such as routers, smartwatches, televisions, and hybrid vehicles.
- I am involved in the complete life-cycle of the embedded software product, from building the through to final testing and device implementation .
- Spend time in Debugging to find the root cause of the problems.

#### Education

PG Diploma in Internet of Things

CDAC at Bengluru August 2019 - March 2020

- To use advanced analytical tools/ decision-making tools/operation Research
   Techniques to analyze complex problems and get ready to develop new techniques for
   the futures.
- Learn Big Data Technology, Cloud Computing, Networks, Programming, Micro controllers.
- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science Engineer

Shri Shankaracharya Engineering College at Bhilai, Chhattisgarh April 2015 - May 2019

### **Projects**

Smart Logistics Management System

| August 2019 - March 2020

- The project proposes to manage logistics with better tracking, with additional analysis
  of quality, sustenance, material etc. and aiding with required user interface.
- We will be implanting some micro-controllers coupled with different sensors on different stages of an industry and will be using block chain mechanism on the supply chain of that industry to monitor its distribution mechanism from the manufacturer till the customer.
- The technologies generally used are Python, MySQL, MongoDB, PySpark, Android studio, Raspberry Pi, Temperature and Humidity Sensor, MOTT, NodeJS